<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Python on Geospatial Python Developer</title>
    <link>https://geopy.dev/tags/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Python on Geospatial Python Developer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 10:29:26 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://geopy.dev/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Q: How to quickly calculate turf per maintenance area?</title>
      <link>https://geopy.dev/how-much-of-one-area-within-another/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 10:29:26 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geopy.dev/how-much-of-one-area-within-another/</guid>
      <description>Showing turf over maintenance areas.   A: Python in ArcGIS Pro: arcpy.analysis.SummarizeWithin(&amp;#34;maintenance_area_pgon&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;turf_area_gpon&amp;#34;, r&amp;#34;path\to\save\output\file&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;KEEP_ALL&amp;#34;, None, &amp;#34;ADD_SHAPE_SUM&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;SQUAREFEET&amp;#34;, None, &amp;#34;NO_MIN_MAJ&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;NO_PERCENT&amp;#34;, r&amp;#34;path\to\save\group\table&amp;#34;) The parameters for Summarize Within are SummarizeWithin_analysis (in_polygons, in_sum_features, out_feature_class, {keep_all_polygons}, {sum_fields}, {sum_shape}, {shape_unit}, {group_field}, {add_min_maj}, {add_group_percent}, {out_group_table})
For the full docs have a look at esri&amp;rsquo;s documentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Common Field Calculations in ArcGIS</title>
      <link>https://geopy.dev/common-arcgis-field-calculations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2019 08:21:04 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geopy.dev/common-arcgis-field-calculations/</guid>
      <description>The ArcGIS field calculator can save a person time and allow for fairly quick data cleanup IF you can remember how to use it. I don&amp;rsquo;t know about you, but for me the layout of the field calculator, the separation of the formula field and the code block area and the minor changes from standard Python formatting are enough to send me straight to the Google search bar if I haven&amp;rsquo;t used it in a while.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Python to Update ArcGIS Online Services</title>
      <link>https://geopy.dev/use-python-to-update-arcgis-online-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 10:56:42 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geopy.dev/use-python-to-update-arcgis-online-services/</guid>
      <description>The problem: It&amp;rsquo;s tough to keep an ever changing underground utility model up to date. It is especially difficult when your audience uses a variety of methods to access that data. The majority of my audience accesses this data via hosted PDFs but an ever growing group is now using ArcGIS Explorer and ArcGIS Collector on smartphones and tablets to access the same set of data.
Since I manage the GIS data model of over ten types of utilities across multiple formats it was becoming quite common for a change to be made on my desktop but then either the PDF print or ArcGIS Online hosted data to be out of sync.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Export ArcGIS Data Driven Pages &amp; Sync Using Python and Google Drive</title>
      <link>https://geopy.dev/automate-export-to-pdf-of-arcgis-desktop-data-driven-pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 13:00:23 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geopy.dev/automate-export-to-pdf-of-arcgis-desktop-data-driven-pages/</guid>
      <description>Quick Background: I work at UC Santa Barbara and one of my many jobs is to keep our underground utility atlas up to date. This atlas is accessed in multiple formats including PDF, desktop, and mobile applications. The campus atlas sheets are broken up to 500x500 foot grids which each represent a single sheet when printed or viewed as a PDF. The entire Santa Barbara campus makes up just over 300 of these grids.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>